[☰](javascript:void(0);)

Statement of Privacy
====================

> **We respect your privacy! Ever since our website www.neuber.com came on line in 1997, we have been taking the utmost care with your data and treating it with the highest standards of confidentiality. This begins with keeping data to a minimum or not gathering it at all. Thus we do not use any behavior tracking or sharing tools, and we avoid using cookies wherever possible. Your IP addresses are either anonymized or blocked within the CDN. This keeps our websites thin and fast. Whenever Adsense, Custom Search Engine or the like come into play, we always use settings with the highest degree of data-protection friendliness—meaning no remarketing, no profiling, no interest- or behavior-based advertising, no cross device tracking, no user id, only anonymous transmission of IP, minimal caching, and so on. This is our way of ensuring that even third parties can obtain only minimal information about your surfing behavior, or none at all. Even when buying our software, you can remain anonymous and you do not have to provide a complete address. All this is intended to safeguard your personal data.**
> 
>   
> 
> Personal data (usually referred to just as "data" below) will only be processed by us to the extent necessary and for the purpose of providing a functional and user-friendly website, including its contents, and the services offered there.
> 
> Per Art. 4 No. 1 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679, i.e. the General Data Protection Regulation (hereinafter referred to as the "GDPR"), "processing" refers to any operation or set of operations such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation, alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination, or otherwise making available, alignment, or combination, restriction, erasure, or destruction performed on personal data, whether by automated means or not.
> 
> The following privacy policy is intended to inform you in particular about the type, scope, purpose, duration, and legal basis for the processing of such data either under our own control or in conjunction with others. We also inform you below about the third-party components we use to optimize our website and improve the user experience which may result in said third parties also processing data they collect and control.
> 
> Our privacy policy is structured as follows:
> 
> I. Information about us as controllers of your data  
> II. The rights of users and data subjects  
> III. Information about the data processing
> 
> ### I. Information about us as controllers of your data
> 
> The party responsible for this website (the "controller") for purposes of data protection law is:
> 
> QS4gJiBNLąOZXViċIgU29 dHdhc U8YnI+UG9zdGZhY2ggMTEĭDUĭjĜĞĠMDYwĮkgSGFsbGĳKFNĩWxlKTxicj5HċJtYW55PGJyP VŘWlsOąpb ZvQG5ldWJlci5jb20=
> 
> ### II. The rights of users and data subjects
> 
> With regard to the data processing to be described in more detail below, users and data subjects have the right
> 
> * to confirmation of whether data concerning them is being processed, information about the data being processed, further information about the nature of the data processing, and copies of the data (cf. also Art. 15 GDPR);
> * to correct or complete incorrect or incomplete data (cf. also Art. 16 GDPR);
> * to the immediate deletion of data concerning them (cf. also Art. 17 DSGVO), or, alternatively, if further processing is necessary as stipulated in Art. 17 Para. 3 GDPR, to restrict said processing per Art. 18 GDPR;
> * to receive copies of the data concerning them and/or provided by them and to have the same transmitted to other providers/controllers (cf. also Art. 20 GDPR);
> * to file complaints with the supervisory authority if they believe that data concerning them is being processed by the controller in breach of data protection provisions (see also Art. 77 GDPR).
> 
> In addition, the controller is obliged to inform all recipients to whom it discloses data of any such corrections, deletions, or restrictions placed on processing the same per Art. 16, 17 Para. 1, 18 GDPR. However, this obligation does not apply if such notification is impossible or involves a disproportionate effort. Nevertheless, users have a right to information about these recipients.
> 
> **Likewise, under Art. 21 GDPR, users and data subjects have the right to object to the controller's future processing of their data pursuant to Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. In particular, an objection to data processing for the purpose of direct advertising is permissible.**
> 
> ### III. Information about the data processing
> 
> Your data processed when using our website will be deleted or blocked as soon as the purpose for its storage ceases to apply, provided the deletion of the same is not in breach of any statutory storage obligations or unless otherwise stipulated below.
> 
> #### Server data
> 
> For technical reasons, the following data sent by your internet browser to us or to our server provider will be collected, especially to ensure a secure and stable website: These server log files record the type and version of your browser, operating system, the website from which you came (referrer URL), the webpages on our site visited, the date and time of your visit, as well as the IP address from which you visited our site.
> 
> The data thus collected will be temporarily stored, but not in association with any other of your data.
> 
> The basis for this storage is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Our legitimate interest lies in the improvement, stability, functionality, and security of our website.
> 
> The data will be deleted within no more than seven days, unless continued storage is required for evidentiary purposes. In which case, all or part of the data will be excluded from deletion until the investigation of the relevant incident is finally resolved.
> 
> #### Cookies
> 
> ##### a) Session cookies
> 
> We use cookies on our website. Cookies are small text files or other storage technologies stored on your computer by your browser. These cookies process certain specific information about you, such as your browser, location data, or IP address.  
> 
> This processing makes our website more user-friendly, efficient, and secure, allowing us, for example, to display our website in different languages or to offer a shopping cart function.
> 
> The legal basis for such processing is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. b) GDPR, insofar as these cookies are used to collect data to initiate or process contractual relationships.
> 
> If the processing does not serve to initiate or process a contract, our legitimate interest lies in improving the functionality of our website. The legal basis is then Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.
> 
> When you close your browser, these session cookies are deleted.
> 
> ##### b) Third-party cookies
> 
> If necessary, our website may also use cookies from companies with whom we cooperate for the purpose of advertising, analyzing, or improving the features of our website.
> 
> Please refer to the following information for details, in particular for the legal basis and purpose of such third-party collection and processing of data collected through cookies.
> 
> ##### c) Disabling cookies
> 
> You can refuse the use of cookies by changing the settings on your browser. Likewise, you can use the browser to delete cookies that have already been stored. However, the steps and measures required vary, depending on the browser you use. If you have any questions, please use the help function or consult the documentation for your browser or contact its maker for support. Browser settings cannot prevent so-called flash cookies from being set. Instead, you will need to change the setting of your Flash player. The steps and measures required for this also depend on the Flash player you are using. If you have any questions, please use the help function or consult the documentation for your Flash player or contact its maker for support.
> 
> If you prevent or restrict the installation of cookies, not all of the functions on our site may be fully usable.
> 
> #### Order processing
> 
> The data you submit when ordering goods and/or services from us will have to be processed in order to fulfill your order. Please note that orders cannot be processed without providing this data.
> 
> The legal basis for this processing is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.
> 
> After your order has been completed, your personal data will be deleted, but only after the retention periods required by tax and commercial law.
> 
> In order to process your order, we will share your data with the shipping company responsible for delivery to the extent required to deliver your order and/or with the payment service provider to the extent required to process your payment.
> 
> ##### The legal basis for the transfer of this data is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.
> 
> #### Newsletter
> 
> If you register for our free newsletter, the data requested from you for this purpose, i.e. your email address and, optionally, your name and address, will be sent to us. We also store the IP address of your computer and the date and time of your registration. During the registration process, we will obtain your consent to receive this newsletter and the type of content it will offer, with reference made to this privacy policy. The data collected will be used exclusively to send the newsletter and will not be passed on to third parties.
> 
> The legal basis for this is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. a) GDPR.
> 
> You may revoke your prior consent to receive this newsletter under Art. 7 Para. 3 GDPR with future effect. All you have to do is inform us that you are revoking your consent or click on the unsubscribe link contained in each newsletter.
> 
> #### Contact
> 
> If you contact us via email or the contact form, the data you provide will be used for the purpose of processing your request. We must have this data in order to process and answer your inquiry; otherwise we will not be able to answer it in full or at all.
> 
> The legal basis for this data processing is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.
> 
> Your data will be deleted once we have fully answered your inquiry and there is no further legal obligation to store your data, such as if an order or contract resulted therefrom.
> 
> #### User posts, comments, and ratings
> 
> We offer you the opportunity to post questions, answers, opinions, and ratings on our website, hereinafter referred to jointly as "posts." If you make use of this opportunity, we will process and publish your post, the date and time you submitted it, and any pseudonym you may have used.
> 
> The legal basis for this is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. a) GDPR. You may revoke your prior consent under Art. 7 Para. 3 GDPR with future effect. All you have to do is inform us that you are revoking your consent.
> 
> In addition, we will also process your IP address and email address. The IP address is processed because we might have a legitimate interest in taking or supporting further action if your post infringes the rights of third parties and/or is otherwise unlawful.
> 
> In this case, the legal basis is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Our legitimate interest lies in any legal defense we may have to mount.
> 
> #### Google AdSense
> 
> We use Google AdSense on our website to integrate advertisements. This is a service provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 (hereinafter: Google).
> 
> Through certification according to the EU-US Privacy Shield
> 
> [https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active)
> 
> Google guarantees that it will follow the EU's data protection regulations when processing data in the United States.
> 
> Google AdSense stores cookies and web beacons on your device via your browser. This enables Google to analyze how you use our website. In addition to your IP address and the advertising formats displayed, the information thus collected will be transmitted to Google in the USA and stored there. Google may also share this information with third parties. Google states that it will not connect your IP address to other data.
> 
> The legal basis is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Our legitimate interest lies in the analysis, optimization, and economic operation of our site.
> 
> If you do not agree to this processing, you have the option of preventing the installation of cookies by making the appropriate settings in your browser. Further details can be found in the section about cookies above.
> 
> In addition, Google offers an opt-out add-on at
> 
> 
> 
> in particular on options for preventing the use of data.
> 
> #### Cloudflare
> 
> We use SSL encryption (https) and the "Content Delivery Network," provided by Cloudflare, Inc., 101 Townsend St, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA as authorized by our legitimate interest under Article 6, Paragraph 1 (f.) of the GDPR, in allowing our visitors to view our pages quickly and securely. Cloudflare provides its own servers and infrastructure for this purpose. Through certification by the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework[https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnZKAA0&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnZKAA0&status=Active) Cloudflare guarantees that the EU data protection requirements will be observed even when data are processed in the USA. Cloudflare’s data privacy policy can be found at: [https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/)
> 
> #### Information/Cancellation/Deletion
> 
> On the basis of the Federal Data Protection Act, you may contact us at no cost if you have questions relating to the collection, processing or use of your personal information, if you wish to request the correction, blocking or deletion of the same, or if you wish to cancel explicitly granted consent. Please note that you have the right to have incorrect data corrected or to have personal data deleted, where such claim is not barred by any legal obligation to retain this data.
> 
> This Privacy Policy Statement was provided by the [Law Offices of Weiß & Partner](https://www.ratgeberrecht.eu/leistungen/muster-datenschutzerklaerung.html)

|     |     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
| [")](https://www.microsoft.com/solution-providers/partnerdetails/neubercom_cec61641-57ec-43dd-b468-45f768475fed/7fa1450b-eb5b-447a-b6b6-05a099c33e22) |  | [](https://www.neuber.com/donation.html) | ") | **neuber.com is safe**  <br> [Norton™ Safe Web](https://safeweb.norton.com/report/show?url=neuber.com)  <br> [McAfee® SECURE™](https://www.mcafeesecure.com/verify?host=www.neuber.com)  <br> [WOT® Reputation](https://www.mywot.com/scorecard/neuber.com)  <br> [VirusTotal Clean](https://www.virustotal.com/gui/url/f610d3e12cd325ac49bc908ca61301808cccc45962d074050ad8aeb614a49901/detection) |
